Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
Kimi yo hashire
You must run forth!
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Kyodai na teki o
You must fight the towering foe!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Kimi yo tsukame
You must seize the power!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
A half-century has passed since humanity began moving...
...its burgeoning population into space.
These gigantic space colonies orbiting the Earth...
...became a second home to humanity...
...where people were born and raised...
...and where they died.
It is the year 0079 of the Universal Century.
The colonies of Side 3 proclaimed themselves
the Principality of Zeon.
It launched a war of independence
against the Earth Federation.
During this war, the Principality of Zeon
and the Federation...
...caused the deaths
of half the total population.
Humanity was horrified by its own actions.
Re-entry to Earth
Here's some soap and a towel.
Here you go. You'll be all refreshed
when you step onto the Earth.
Amuro?
Come on! You've gotta fix it!
I-I'm sure it can be fixed...
Oh, Amuro...
Let's see...
Could I take a look?
Can you fix it?
Please let me try.
Can you really?
Thank you.
Ever since he lost his parents...
...he does nothing but play with this all day.
They were lost in the war?
In the One Week Battle.
How about yourself?
My mother should still be on Earth.
My father went missing at Side 7.
Here.
Yay!
When we get to Earth,
I want to take him to where I grew up.
I never thought I'd be able
to set foot on Earth again.
Before I came to Side 7...
...I had a coffee plantation in South America.
Ever seen these before? Coffee beans.
When I get back to Earth...
...I'm just going to stay put.
Even if Zeon were to invade...
Even if the Earth Federation big shots
order me to leave.
I want to be buried on Earth.
Atmospheric entry in 25 minutes.
Think you can handle it, Mirai?
I did an atmospheric entry
once in a space glider.
But that time, I was able to use
terrestrial communications networks.
And it was a totally different craft.
The basic navigation is the same.
Just follow the Salamis's lead.
I'm just worried because...
...I can't believe that Char has
simply gone away.
Mirai, I want you to concentrate entirely
on the atmospheric entry.
Yes, sir.
Hey, kid! Do you read me?
Yes, Lt. Reed.
Are you prepared for atmospheric entry?
We'll be in the Salamis's re-entry capsule.
We'll be going faster than your vessel...
so don't fall behind.
Yes, sir. Roger that.
Mirai, switch to auto-pilot for entry.
Make all preparations for entry.
Yes, sir.
Char's Musai?
Still there. But a ship is approaching it.
What? Is Char trying to
take on supplies again?
Wait a minute.
if they're getting re-supplied now...
...maybe they've given up the chase.
Fortunately, the three new Zakus
reached us in time.
We enter the atmosphere in 20 minutes.
Launching an attack with this kind of timing
is unprecedented.
If you're pulled in by Earth's gravity,
and atmospheric friction begins...
...even a Zaku will burn up in an instant.
However...
Since the enemy's attention...
...is completely focused on the entry...
...this is our chance to attack with the Zakus.
First objective, the Trojan Horse.
Second objective, the enemy mobile suit.
We have less than 2 minutes for combat.
But I'm sure you're capable
of carrying out this operation.
Good luck!
Those going to Earth will transfer
to the re-entry capsule.
As for the Salamis itself...
...it will return to Luna II
once the capsule is launched.
Camilla, are you confident you can
outrun the Musai?
I can't say that I'm confident.
But we can hope for the best.
According to our data,
the Musai has docked with the Sodon.
Either it's being re-supplied,
or there's been an emergency.
I doubt it will come after us.
You're always so optimistic.
Yes, sir. I believe that's why I'm still alive.
Well, I must prepare to descend to Earth.
Yes, sir.
Standby with missiles.
Yes, sir!
I wonder, will Char follow us.
I doubt it, sir.
Salamis capsule is launched.
The White Base will follow the capsule.
Attention, White Base personnel...
The ship will enter the atmosphere
in 8 minutes.
Please be seated.
Remain calm, even if there's turbulence.
Combat personnel and mechanics
stand by at your stations.
We may have to deploy the Gundam.
Mechanics, be on alert.
Enemies!
I've got a visual. Maximum magnification.
Contact estimated in 34 seconds!
Open the hatch!
Launch the Gundam immediately!
Amuro, return to the White Base
after 4 minutes. No exceptions.
Roger.
After all, Ms. Sayla,
I don't want to burn up either.
Four Zakus to stern, R, 3 degrees.
Four Zakus?!
But Char shouldn't have any Zakus left.
Isn't that right, Ms. Sayla?
You have to face the facts.
Can the White Base back me up?
Kai and Ryu will cover you with
the rear missiles and machine guns.
Just watch your altitude.
How can I watch my altitude
in the middle of combat?!
You can do it.
Don't flatter me.
There they are.
The enemy's launched its mobile suit, too.
Give me cover, Dren.
We'll split into two, and then attack.
Roger.
Launching re-entry capsule.
Ready! Launch!
Musai!
Launch missiles!
Missiles behind you!
Lieutenant Reed, please descend!
Can't we return?
Impossible! We'll just be shot down!
They're too far.
Second wave of missiles! Evade!
Why haven't the rear defensive
missiles been fired?!
Stay calm, Bright. No one's used to this.
Why aren't you firing back?!
I was never trained to operate missiles!
You see?
Dammit!
Do something if you don't want to die!
There should be a manual somewhere!
Grandpa!
Don't worry. The young man who
fixed your car will get the enemy.
You're right...
This time I'll match Char, move for move.
How many times has this been, Amuro?!
I'm not letting you near the White Base.
What?!
Char!
Amuro, don't get too distracted by Char.
The Zakus are after the Salamis capsule.
Roger!
I don't like turning my back on Char, but...
You idiot!
My shield!
Where's Char?!
I won't let you!
There!
Oh no!
The spare bazooka ammo...!
Ms. Sayla, can you send me the beam rifle?
Impossible. I can't launch the rifle now.
But I'll ask the mechanics.
Take the left machine gun!
What?! But I...
I've never fired one before either!
Ryu! Hayato!
The Zakus are too close for missile fire.
Use the machine guns!
Roger!
Char!
Amuro! We can only send you
the Gundam Hammer right now!
That's fine!
Roger! I'll let you know when we launch it.
In front! Amuro!
I see him!
He's got vulcan guns in there!
No! No! Lt. Commander Char!
Lt. Commander Char! Help me!
Lt. Commander Char! Sir!
I can't hit it.
Are the Vulcan barrels misaligned?
Amuro!
We're launching the Gundam Hammer, okay?
The relative speed is too fast...
Can I catch it?!
Char!
This is it!
Damn you, Char!
Mobile Suit
Damn! I've lost my spare!
Our approach angle's too deep!
Can we still do it?!
Can't say for sure, sir! However...
The ceiling...!
Lt. Reed, your normal suit!
Hurry! We're decompressing!
Get the normal suit sealing tape!
Something's on fire! Put it out!
Yes, sir!
Lieutenant, are you injured?
Focus on the suit! The wound will heal!
Yes, sir!
Can't you be more careful?!
The Salamis capsule's been hit!
Can they still attempt atmospheric entry?
I don't know!
Mr. Bright! At this rate,
the capsule will burn up from the inside!
I understand, sir.
The White Base will bring you in.
Please...!
Sayla, tell Amuro to draw away
the two Zakus.
That's impossible!
He's got his hands full fighting Char!
Accelerating by 10%.
We'll move in front of the capsule.
Amuro! We're bringing in the Salamis capsule.
Get ready!
Kai! Ryu! Provide anti-air cover!
The bastards are moving too fast!
Hatch is open.
Salamis capsule, do you read?
We'll use the laser lock.
It'll move automatically once locked.
Roger!
I just hope they can pull this off.
Activating laser lock!
Crown, what are you doing?
By now, you should know where
the enemy is firing from.
Approach and hit it.
You must use the Zaku's full potential!
But sir, the barrage is too intense...!
This is nothing.
Target and hit them from below.
Kom! Can you keep up with me?
Yes, Lt. Commander! No problem!
It's only the Zaku's right arm that's dead.
I can use the heat hawk with my left arm!
Excellent. You've managed well.
We'll hit the enemy's mobile suit.
Amuro! A Zaku's moving in
below the White Base! Get him!
What's the situation?
Not good, sir.
Damage on starboard!
Fire the starboard machine guns!
Deploy wall film to the breach! Hurry!
Block 4, wall film! Anybody there?!
I want to go and fight them too!
This is a war, you know!
I'm not afraid!
It's really scary!
Where are the side machine gun turrets?
Should be in Number 35!
The one on starboard aims forward!
Let's do it!
He's not letting me get up above him!
This pilot's improving rapidly!
Well done, Kom!
Don't underestimate us!
Kom!
No time left.
Amuro, get back to White Base.
You're over the time limit.
Roger, Ms. Sayla! But first...
This is it, Char!
Crown, get back to Dren's capsule!
Crown. Crown! Can't you hear me?
Entering atmosphere!
Raise defense shutters!
Bring the Gundam in from the rear hatch.
Securing machine gun turrets!
Amuro, enter from the White Base rear hatch!
You're cutting it close!
Roger!
But I still have ammo for the vulcans!
I'll get him first!
Lt. Commander Char!
Please get in the capsule!
Right. Open the hatch.
Forget it, Crown.
Even that enemy suit wouldn't risk it.
Head for the capsule now.
Tell Amuro that the Gundam will burn up
from the atmospheric friction!
Get back here, Amuro! Forget the Zaku!
Mr. Bright...!
My mission here...
...is to safely deliver the White Base
and the Gundam to Federation HQ!
Bring the Gundam in!
Tell Amuro that.
This is what happens with amateurs!
But if I hadn't sent the Gundam out,
they'd have destroyed the White Base.
Please sit down, Lt. Reed.
It's not safe.
Bring outer hull cooling system
up 3 points.
I'll have you court-martialed! Got that?!
Amuro... Hasn't Amuro returned yet?!
The acceleration... I'm falling too fast!
Where's Crown?
Unfortunately, it's too late to recover him.
Lt. Commander Char!
Please help me! I can't slow down!
Lt. Commander Char, help me!
Crown... The Zaku isn't capable
of atmospheric entry.
I'm sorry, there's nothing I can do...
But Crown, your death will not be in vain.
Because you were able to draw in
the enemy mobile suit with you...
...we can destroy it!
Here it is! Atmospheric entry process!
But can I do it in time?
Attitude adjustment... Cooling shift...
Connecting all circuits!
Heat-proof film!
Incredible!
The armor temperature's gone down!
But how am I going to land?
I can't monitor the Gundam
due to radio interference.
Amuro! Amuro! Please respond!
Amuro... Amuro!
We can't make contact for a while.
The mobile suit hasn't changed position.
It's not burning up, either!
What can this mean?!
Does it have the ability
to enter the atmosphere?
It's hard to believe, but...
...given that the Trojan Horse can
enter the atmosphere on its own...
...it is possible. Unfortunately for us.
Altitude 32... 30...
29... 26... 25... 24...
20... 17...
16... 14...
12... 11...
Is it going to hold up?
When we have radio communications,
contact Captain Garma of the ground forces.
I think I understand now,
Lt. Commander Char.
Even if we weren't able to defeat
the enemy before re-entry...
...by making them change
their approach angle...
...you're forcing the Trojan Horse
onto a Zeon-controlled continent.
A brilliant two-stage operation.
War is cruel business.
I have to plan for every eventuality.
It's Captain Garma.
Well, what is it, Red Comet?
I might have to give up that nickname,
Captain Garma Zabi.
You're unusually subdued today.
Ever heard of the enemy's Operation V?
I've uncovered it.
What's that?
Thanks to Operation V,
I've lost eight Zakus.
How terrible. It's that formidable?
I've lured the enemy into your area.
I'm sure It'll be good for your record.
I'll be there soon.
Well, I'll accept your generous gift.
I'll intercept them with a Gaw attack carrier.
Emergency launch!
Yes, sir!
Altitude, 53,000. Decelerating steadily.
We're resuming level flight.
Good. Amuro! Do you read me? Amuro!
Amuro! The comm should be working now!
Amuro, please answer me! Amuro!
Visuals are back online.
It's the Gundam!
Amuro!
That kid.
I'll have to have a word with him later.
But the Federation can beat Zeon
with this mobile suit.
Radio comm is back. Returning to ship!
Reception is good.
Amuro, you can step onto the rear deck.
Roger!
Now look at that, Pelo! That's Earth!
Wow! Is that all land?
And this part over here is called the sea?
That's right. I guess this is the first time
you've seen the Earth with your own eyes.
It's a natural planet, Pelo,
made up of land and sea.
This is our projected approach angle.
This is our course up to now.
This doesn't do us any good, Mr. Bright!
I agree. We're deep in Zeon territory.
This is no laughing matter...!
Let me take care of that injury.
Char is a clever strategist.
We were led into a trap by Char.
We have to break through, no matter what!
Enemy approaching!
What?!
Maybe it's as Char says.
Compared to previous Federation ships...
...this one's in a class of its own.
It's the Musai capsule, sir.
Good. Bring him in.
Garma Zabi's forces...
...pin the White Base close to the ground.
Fighting trained soldiers means
there's not a moment to spare.
Furthermore...
Earth's gravity presents new challenges
for Amuro and the crew.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Garma Strikes!
Next Time
Garma Strikes
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...